<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pixel Automation – Installation</title><link>https://nfactor26.github.io/pixel-automation-docs/docs/installation/</link><description>Recent content in Installation on Pixel Automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://nfactor26.github.io/pixel-automation-docs/docs/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: pixel-deigner</title><link>https://nfactor26.github.io/pixel-automation-docs/docs/installation/pixel-designer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nfactor26.github.io/pixel-automation-docs/docs/installation/pixel-designer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>pixel-designer is a wpf based application built on top of .net core framework. It provides the design environment for creating automation test cases.
It can be executed only on windows operating system. However, it should be possible to execute the test cases designed in pixel-designer on a linux machine as well using pixel-runner as long as test cases use plugins compatible with linux.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Extract the files to any location after unblocking the zip files.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Launch pixel-design.exe and application will be started in offline mode.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Admin rights are not required to execute the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="pixel-designer.PNG" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>pixel-designer can work in online or offline mode. Offline mode is a quick way to try out the software before going through all the required setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="settings">Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Settings window can be opened by clicking the wheel icon on top right. There are three sections :&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>General&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="settings-general.PNG" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Persistence Service : Url of the persistence service if you want to run application in online mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Work Offline : Indicates if application should work in online or offline mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixture&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="settings-fixture.PNG" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Delay Before : Amount of delay in milli seconds before executing each step of the automation workflow.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Delay After : Amount of delay in milli seconds after executing each step of the automation workflow.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Delay Factor : Delay Before and Delay After are scaled using Delay Factor before using those values. Delay Factor can be overridden by individual fixture and test cases.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Theme&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="settings-theme.PNG" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Theme : Theme of the application. It can be light or dark.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Accent : Accent applied to the application. Multiple color options are available for accent.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: pixel-persistence</title><link>https://nfactor26.github.io/pixel-automation-docs/docs/installation/pixel-persistence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nfactor26.github.io/pixel-automation-docs/docs/installation/pixel-persistence/</guid><description>
&lt;p>pixel-persistence is an asp.net core based web service used by pixel-designer and pixel-runner to store and retrieve data. It also comes up with a blazor based UI for showing various reports for test execution results. pixel-persistence requires &lt;a href="https://www.mongodb.com/try/download/community">mongodb&lt;/a> to store automation process and test execution data.
The release only provides a windows OS binary at the moment which can be executed as an standalone application on windows OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>see docker-compose-&lt;em>.&lt;/em> files in &lt;a href="https://github.com/Nfactor26/pixel-automation">project repository&lt;/a> if you are intrested in hosting on docker. Please let us know if you need an official docker image by raising an issue on project &lt;a href="https://github.com/Nfactor26/pixel-automation/issues">isssues&lt;/a> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Make sure that an instance of mongodb is up and running&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the files to any location after unblocking the zip file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure that DOTNET_ENVIRONMENT OR ASPNETCORE_ENVIRONMENT variable is set to production. See &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/aspnet/core/fundamentals/environments?view=aspnetcore-7.0#environments">ENVIRONMENTS&lt;/a> in asp.net&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edit the appsettings.json file to set the MongoDbSettings-&amp;gt;ConnectionString. Example connectionString &amp;ldquo;mongodb://localhost:27017&amp;rdquo;. This will vary based on your mongodb configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Launch pixel-persistence.exe&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to dashboard - https://localhost:5001/persistence and swagger ui - https://localhost:5001/swagger/index.html) to verify service is up and running. Base Url can be different depending on your setup.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>pixel-persistence doesn&amp;rsquo;t support authentication and authorization out of the box. You would ideally want to host it behind a reverse proxy like &lt;a href="https://microsoft.github.io/reverse-proxy/">yarp&lt;/a> and authenticate and authorize requests before they are proxied. Please see &lt;a href="https://microsoft.github.io/reverse-proxy/articles/authn-authz.html">Authentication and Authorization&lt;/a> with yarp. You can use any reverse proxy of your choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Docs: pixel-runner</title><link>https://nfactor26.github.io/pixel-automation-docs/docs/installation/pixel-runner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nfactor26.github.io/pixel-automation-docs/docs/installation/pixel-runner/</guid><description>
&lt;p>pixel-runner is a .net core cli based application that can be used to execute test cases designed in pixel-designer. It is suitable for use on your machines dedicated for execution of test cases.
Although, pixel-runner can be used on both windows and linux machines, only windows binaries are available at the moment as part of releases.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Extract the files to any location after unblocking the zip files.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edit the appsettings.json and set &amp;ldquo;persistenceServiceUri&amp;rdquo; to the url of persistence-service.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Launch command prompt and change working directory to the folder contaning pixel-run.exe&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Run pixel-run &amp;ndash;help from the command prompt to see help menu.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Admin rights are not required to execute the application&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="pixel-run.PNG" alt="">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>